<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hypertidy website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hypertidy website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web services for scientific data in R</title>
      <link>/2017/07/25/erddap-in-sf-and-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/25/erddap-in-sf-and-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>This post is in-progress …
Two very important packages in R are rerddap and plotdap providing straightforward access to and visualization of time-varying gridded data sets. Traditionally this is handled by individuals who either have or quickly gain expert knowledge about the minute details regarding obtaining data sources, exploring and extracting data from them, manipulating the data for the required purpose and reporting results. Often this task is not the primary goal, it’s simply a requirement for comparison to environmental data or validation of direct measurements or modelled scenarios against independent data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 11:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a blogdown website for the hypertidy family of R packages for multi-dimensional and spatial data.
Hypertidy is an approach to spatial or multi-dimensional data in R based on the following principles:
 data sources are best managed with database techniques spatial is not special, user-interfaces, graphics and time-series all involve &amp;lsquo;space&amp;rsquo; raster and vector are not naturally distinct, high-dimensional, curvilinear, cell-based rasters, polygon grids and ragged-arrays all cross this boundary &amp;lsquo;mesh-based&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;indexed&amp;rsquo; data structures are central, general data types while traditionally &amp;ldquo;geospatial&amp;rdquo; structures are domain-specific optimizations simple features left topology behind, resulting in fragmented and inefficient workarounds in the geo-spatial communities R spatial needs better APIs, a rich ecosystem of small, composable software modules tidy data principles are about leveraging databases and database techniques  Examples of these principles are seen in these R packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello hypertidy</title>
      <link>/2017/06/12/hello-hypertidy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/12/hello-hypertidy/</guid>
      <description>Hypertidy Website for the hypertidy family of R packages for multi-dimensional and spatial data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypertidy manifesto</title>
      <link>/manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Gridded data Hypertidy recognizes that not all gridded data fit into the GIS raster conventions. Gridded data comes in many forms, geographic with longitude-latitude or projected spaces, with time and or depth dimensions, with different orderings of axes (i.e. time-first, the latitude-longitude), and with generally any arbitrary space. A space is simply a set of axes with particular units and projection, and yes we mean &amp;ldquo;space&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;projection&amp;rdquo; in the more general mathematical sense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>