<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hypertidy website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hypertidy website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 11:47:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 11:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a blogdown website for the hypertidy family of R packages for multi-dimensional and spatial data.
Hypertidy is an approach to spatial or multi-dimensional data in R based on the following principles:
 data sources are best managed with database techniques spatial is not special, user-interfaces, graphics and time-series all involve &amp;lsquo;space&amp;rsquo; raster and vector are not naturally distinct, high-dimensional, curvilinear, cell-based rasters, polygon gris and ragged-arrays all cross this boundary &amp;lsquo;mesh-based&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;indexed&amp;rsquo; data structures are central, general data types while traditionally &amp;ldquo;geospatial&amp;rdquo; structures are domain-specific optimizations simple features left topology behind, resulting in fragmented and inefficient workarounds in the geo-spatial communities R spatial needs better APIs, a rich ecosystem of small, composable software modules tidy data principles are about leveraging databases and database techniques  Examples of these principles are seen in these R packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello hypertidy</title>
      <link>/2017/06/12/hello-hypertidy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/12/hello-hypertidy/</guid>
      <description>Hypertidy Website for the hypertidy family of R packages for multi-dimensional and spatial data</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>