<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hypertidy website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hypertidy website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GDAL in R</title>
      <link>/2017/09/01/gdal-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/01/gdal-in-r/</guid>
      <description>For some time I have used GDAL as a standard tool in my kit, I was introduced to the concept by the rgdal package authors and it slowly dawned on what it meant to have a geo-spatial data abstraction library. To realize what this meant I had spent a lot of time in R, reading (primarily) MapInfo TAB and MIF format files as well (of course) as shapefiles, and the occasional GeoTIFF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web services for scientific data in R</title>
      <link>/2017/07/25/erddap-in-sf-and-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/25/erddap-in-sf-and-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>This post is in-progress …
Two very important packages in R are rerddap and plotdap providing straightforward access to and visualization of time-varying gridded data sets. Traditionally this is handled by individuals who either have or quickly gain expert knowledge about the minute details regarding obtaining data sources, exploring and extracting data from them, manipulating the data for the required purpose and reporting results. Often this task is not the primary goal, it’s simply a requirement for comparison to environmental data or validation of direct measurements or modelled scenarios against independent data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello hypertidy</title>
      <link>/2017/06/12/hello-hypertidy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/12/hello-hypertidy/</guid>
      <description>Hypertidy Website for the hypertidy family of R packages for multi-dimensional and spatial data</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>